Yorlan Ramirez

Phone: (973) 619-2369 | Email: Yorlan_Ramirez5493@hotmail.com

Github: https://github.com/Yorlan-r

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yorlan-ramirez-614857249/

Work Portfolio: https://yorlan-r.github.io/React-Portfolio/

Summary

Recent bootcamp graduate from Rutger's with a knack for technical challenges with over 10 years of problem solving skills in current profession. Detail oriented team player, with a strong work ethic and a desire for obtaining and furthering knowledge and expertise.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, JSON, C#

Databases: SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL, MongoDB

Tools: Git, Github, Insomnia, Heroku

Frameworks: React, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, GraphQL, Handlebars, OOP,

Server-side API's, Jest

Projects

React Portfolio | https://yorlan-r.github.io/React-Portfolio/

- Summary: Complete and interactive React.js portfolio
- Role: Full-Stack developer
- Technologies: React.js

Recipes "R" Us | http://127.0.0.1:5500/index.html

- Summary: A team project developed that uses an API to obtain multiple recipes of your choice upon searching up foods that come to mind & a "Dad Joke" API to add some fun!
- Role: Back-End and Front-End.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Portfolio | https://yorlan-r.github.io/React-Portfolio/

- Summary: Personal project to showcase abilities using React.js as well as showing previous projects developed.
- Role: Main developer
- Technologies: React, Node.js, Bootstrap, Jest, Github-pages.

Password Generator | https://yorlan-r.github.io/Password-Generator/

- Summary: A personal project that automatically generates a secure password upon user prompts.
- Role: Main developer.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Education

Rutger's University

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development August 2022 - February 2023

GPA: 3.3

Union County College

Automotive Technology July 2011 - March 2013

Employment

Canadian Aviation Electronics (CAE) July 2023 - present

Simulator Technician maintaining mechanical components as well as updating software and databases related to business aviation.

Prestige Lexus of Ramsey

July 2021 - July 2023

Perform complex diagnostic and repairs on customer vehicles, interact with guests and communicate with management and team members.

Hudson Toyota

April 2012 - July 2022

Perform complex diagnostic and repairs on customer vehicles, interact with guests and communicate with management and team members. Assistant team leader for the used car department, manage vehicle inventories, distribute work and assess cost on vehicular repairs.